There aren’t many parents who would say that raising children is easy.
没多少父母会说养育孩子是件容易的事。
For many people, having children can force parents to choose between career and family.
对很多人而言，有了孩子之后，父母往往要在事业和家庭之间做出抉择。
Sometimes it comes down to finances – sending a child to nursery or hiring a nanny can be a huge financial burden that is unsustainable, while others may feel it’s better to be a hands-on parent.
有时候，这归根结底是经济问题——送孩子去托儿所或是雇保姆，可能会成为难以承受的巨大经济负担；而另一些父母则认为，亲历亲为照顾孩子会更好。
These days, more and more men are choosing to stay at home to look after their offspring.
如今，越来越多的男性选择留在家中照顾子女。
So why are more dads opting to put their careers on hold, and what does the job entail?
那么，为什么越来越多的父亲愿意搁置自己的事业？这份“工作”又需要承担哪些职责呢？
With more women working outside the home than 70 years ago, if the need is there for one parent to stay at home, it could simply come down to who earns more – the biggest breadwinner.
与70年前相比，如今有更多女性外出工作。如果家庭需要父母中的一方留在家中，那么这件事很简单，就看谁的收入更高——谁是家里主要的经济支柱。
And with attitudes changing towards a man’s role in the family, it seems to be easier for them to enter full-time parenthood.
随着人们对男性在家庭中角色的看法逐渐转变，男性成为全职家长也变得更容易被接受。
Sadly, though, men may still face stigmas by choosing to raise their child.
但遗憾的是，选择亲自抚养孩子的男性仍可能面临偏见。
A 2013 study in the US by the Pews Research Center found that 51% of people thought children were better off if a mother is home and doesn’t have a job, while 8% say the same about a father.
皮尤研究中心2013年在美国开展的一项研究显示，51%的人认为，如果母亲不上班、留在家中，孩子会过得更好；而只有8%的人认为父亲留在家中也能达到同样的效果。
But what do parents have to do when they choose to stay with their kids?
那么，选择留在家中陪伴孩子的父母，具体需要做些什么呢？
In the early stages, a baby is totally dependent on a carer.
在孩子很小的时候，婴儿完全依赖照顾者的照料。
The changing of nappies, burping after milk and making sure they feed on time are just some of the vital 24-7 activities an infant relies on.
换尿布、喂完奶后拍嗝、确保孩子按时进食，这些只是婴儿所需的全天候重要照料工作中的一部分。
During this period, many parents take paternity and maternity leave from work.
在这个阶段，许多父母会申请育儿假。
But as a child gets older, it can become less about necessity and more about choice.
但随着孩子逐渐长大，父母留在家中就不再是出于必需，而更多是一种选择。
Rather than opt for a creche, which can prove expensive, either parent may remain at home to educate, protect and play with their child to help them develop and grow.
由于托儿所的费用可能十分高昂，父母中的任何一方都可能选择留在家中，通过教育、保护和陪伴孩子玩耍，帮助孩子健康成长。
It’s a difficult job, with a demanding ‘boss’, but it can also be incredibly rewarding for those willing to do it.
这是一份艰巨的工作，面对的是一位“要求苛刻的老板”，但对于愿意承担这份工作的人来说，它也能带来难以言喻的成就感。
And with attitudes changing towards who should stay at home, maybe more and more fathers will choose to become stay-at-home dads.
随着人们对于谁该留在家中这一问题的看法不断转变，或许会有越来越多的父亲选择成为全职爸爸。